<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analyses on Gurudev Ilangovan</title>
    <link>/analyses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analyses on Gurudev Ilangovan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/analyses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What your whatsapp texts say about you</title>
      <link>/analyses/whatsapp_text_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/whatsapp_text_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Processing Patterns Parsing  Analysis Pet words Overall word usage Word usage by member Word usage made better  ⌚ 4⃣ 😂😋😍 Popular emojis and chronic roflitis Let’s put a smiley on that face  Getting sentient about sentiments  Conclusion   Introduction  Without data, you’re just an another person with an opinion - W. Edwards Deming
 We all have intuitions, questions or even hypotheses if you will about people’s texting patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unweaving Happiness</title>
      <link>/analyses/unweaving_happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/unweaving_happiness/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A word of warning if you are reading from a mobile  Setup Data Munging Missing Adding Continents  Exploration Happiness levels Standard Deviation of happiness Correlation Analysis GDP’s relationship Healthy Life Expectancy Social Support  Prediction Setup Modeling Model Selection Testing our model/Diagnostics Best and Worst Predictions  Conclusion   Introduction The World Happiness Report 2018 by United Nations Sustainable Development Solutions Network (SDSN) based on data from the Gallup World Poll surveys was out a few days ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Taxi Trips</title>
      <link>/analyses/chicago_taxi_trips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/chicago_taxi_trips/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Statistically Significant Four</title>
      <link>/analyses/tennis_big4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/tennis_big4/</guid>
      <description>Why the big 4 deserve all the praise they get… We all know tennis is a competitive sport. Winning one slam is hard so much so that it is probably enough. In the chart below, you might recognize a few of those small bars in the far right - Roger Federer with 19 grand slam titles, Rafa with 16 and so on. But try to recollect five people who constitute the single big bar on the left hand side - people who have won just one slam!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/</guid>
      <description>Polarity   mark.pos { background-color: lightgreen; color: black; } mark.neg{ background-color: pink; color: black; } h1 { display: block; font-size: 1.2em; margin-top: 0.0em; margin-bottom: 0.0em; margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; font-weight: bold; } .indented { margin-left: 5%; margin-right: 5%; }   1_The movie was horrible: -.375The movie was horrible
2_The movie was not good at all: -.283The movie was not good at all
3_The movie was okay: .000The movie was okay</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>