<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Gurudev Ilangovan</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Gurudev Ilangovan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2020 Gurudev Ilangovan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A whirwind tour of classes - I (Leveling up in Python - I)</title>
      <link>/blog/python_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python_class/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Tackling Complexity A toy example without classes Iteration 1 Iteration 2  The same example but let’s be classy Iteration 1 Iteration 2  Conclusion   Introduction Welcome to the first post in the leveling up in Python series! In this article, I want to talk about how classes are useful to me. I am by no means an expert in program design or “Object Oriented Programming”. As a teen (and still do sometimes) I detested terms like encapsulation, polymorphism, abstraction, etc because they weren’t tangible concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveling up in Python - 0</title>
      <link>/blog/python_level_up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python_level_up/</guid>
      <description>“Series Intro”…. I started getting into a python seriously about a year ago. I tried learning the language a couple of times before that - I watched a lot of introductory tutorials in the hope of getting good at it. There was one really good one - Corey Schafer’s Python tutorials on YouTube. Barring that, most of the tutorials were basic and went over the same things over and over again - variables, conditionals, loops, functions, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNN - ML from Scratch - Part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/ml_scratch_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ml_scratch_1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Techniques and Design Setup (Libraries and Data) Standardizer K Nearest Neighbours Creating a KNN classifier Fitting a classifier Prediction Score Code  Verifying the results using scikit-learn   pre { white-space: pre !important; # overflow-y: visible !important; max-height: 500vh !important; }  Introduction For my Machine Learing class at A&amp;amp;M, I implemented common ML algorithms from the ground up. It’s amazing how easy it is to implement an ML technique in python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Record Linkage</title>
      <link>/projects/interactive_rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/interactive_rl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UAS constraint satisfacion</title>
      <link>/projects/uav_csp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/uav_csp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UAV path planning</title>
      <link>/projects/uav_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/uav_path/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>